Murtuzaali Surti

Software Engineer Vadodara, IN (+91 8160465102)

With over 1.5 years of experience, I am a software engineer usually dealing with JavaScript. Well versed in building responsive and elegant web designs, and related frontend/backend frameworks, seeking a full-time role to further improve the skillset while at the same time contribute to the organization as well as the developer community.

mail: hey.murtuza@gmail.com github: murtuzaalisurti web: murtuzaalisurti.github.io linkedin: murtuzaalisurti

Work Experience

Software Engineer - Imriel May, 2023 - Present

• Working on an enterprise application related to the management of legal entities of a business. Mainly working with Node, NestJS, PostgreSQL and Docker leaning more towards the backend side.

• Re-designed the backend architecture to support storing multiple client data into a single PostgreSQL database instance in a multi-tenant architecture. Tackled massive performance issues due to this change.

SWE Intern - Imriel Jan, 2023 - May, 2023

• Worked on React, Typescript, MUI and Jest as a Frontend Software Engineer.

Creator - Syntackle Feb, 2022 - Present

Built a blog from scratch using 11ty with some progressive JS. Gulp, Rollup, PostCSS are also a part of the build process. It's mainly a
software development blog covering topics & tutorials related to the web, CSS, JavaScript, dev tools, Jamstack, serverless and much
more. - syntackle.com

Projects

- Syntackle A developer blog built using a static site generator named 11ty.
- Wavy A JavaScript library which allows you to animate infinite words in an infinite loop in a modern wavy way!
- <u>rssed</u> A collection of RSS feeds of hundreds of independent developers as well as publications which updated itself everyday.
- <u>Contact Card</u> A digital business contact card generator which is quick to share.

Education

Navrachana University - Bachelor of Computer Applications Grade: 8.99 (CGPA) July, 2020 - May 2023

Talks & Achievements

- The voice of simplicity What the JAM podcast (Featured Talk)
- <u>Building Projects & Learning Mindset as a Developer</u> Ganesh Patil's Podcast (Featured Talk)
- <u>Top 7 Author Of the Week</u> on DEV.to
- Gave a talk at HacktoberFest 2021 at Navrachana University.

Skills

Programming Languages: JavaScript/TypeScript, Java, HTML, CSS.

Frameworks/Tools/Libraries/Database: React, NestJS, NodeJS, Express, Docker, SQL, PostgreSQL, Astro, 11ty, Markdown, EJS, bash, Git

Murtuzaali Surti 1